dpa.com 2019-09-02

# dpa: Privacy Policy

#### Table of Contents 

1\. General Information     

a. Contact

b. General Information on Data Processing

c. Storage Duration          

d. Technical Service Providers      

e. Security                  

2\. Processing of Server Log Files            

3\. Contact Forms            

4\. dpa Whitepaper          

5\. Newsletter

6\. Surveys

7\. Cookies                 

8\. Google Analytics         

9\. Integrated Services and Third-Party Content         

10\. Google AdWords Conversion Tracking                  

11\. Job Applications           

12\. Information on our Facebook sites              

13\. Your Rights          

14\. Right of Objection           

15\. Withdrawal of Consent

16\. Data Protection Officer

17\. Complaint to a Supervisory Authority

**1\. General Information**

**a. Contact**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this information, or would like to contact us in order to assert your rights, please address your request to  

dpa Deutsche Presse-Agentur GmbH  
Mittelweg 38  
20148 Hamburg  
Phone: 040 4113-0  
Fax: 040 4113-32305  
Email: info@dpa.com  

#### b. General Information on Data Processing

When using this website, personal data may be processed. In terms of data protection legislation, the concept “personal data” refers to all information concerning an identified or identifiable person. An IP address may also be a personal date. An IP address is assigned by the internet provider to every device connected to the internet, so that it is able to send and receive data. We process personal data in compliance with the relevant data protection provisions, in particular of the GDPR and the BDSG. Any data processing on our part occurs exclusively on the basis of legal authorization.  We  process  personal  data  only  with  your  consent  (Art. 6 Par. 1 a) GDPR),  for  the fulfilment of a contract, to which you are a contracting party, or at your request for implementing pre-contractual measures (Art. 6 Par 1 b) GDPR), for compliance with a legal obligation (Art. 6 Par. 1 c) GDPR),  or  if  the  processing  is  necessary  to  secure  our  legitimate  interests  or  the  legitimate interests of a third party, insofar as your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require the protection of personal data, do not override these (Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR). When you submit an application to us, we also process your personal data for the purpose of deciding on the reasons for a relationship of employment (§ 26 Par. 1 BDSG). 

#### c. Storage duration

Insofar as nothing else ensues from the following information, we save the data only for as long as is required  to  achieve  the  purpose  of  the  processing, or  for  the  fulfilment  of  our  contractual  or statutory  obligations.  Statutory  storage  obligation s  of  this  kind  may  arise  in  particular  out  of commercial or fiscal regulations. In this case, we will block the use of your data for other purposes.

#### d. Technical Service Providers

Insofar as nothing else ensues from the following information, the processing of the data occurs on our own servers and, if applicable, on the servers of technical service providers commissioned by us for the purpose within the European Union. These service providers process the data only following express instruction and are contractually bound to maintain adequate technical and organizational measures for data protection. In consequence, our service providers are engaged by us as so-called contracted processors in terms of Art. 28 GDPR.

#### e. Security

dpa  will  take  all  the  necessary  technical  and  organizational  security  measures  to  protect  your personal data against loss or misuse. This means that your data will be saved in a secure operational environment  that  is  not  accessible  to  the  public.  In  certain  cases,  your  personal  data  will  be encrypted during transmission using the so-called Secure Socket Layer technology. This means that the  communication  between  your  computer  and  our  servers  takes  place  using  a  recognized encryption method, provided that your browser supports SSL. 

#### 2\. Processing of Server Log Files

Processing of Server Log Files   
When using our website for the purpose purely of gathering information, general information is saved automatically that your browser transmits to our servers. This includes as standard: Browser type/version, the operating system used, the page called up, the page visited previously (Referrer URL), IP address, date and time of the server request und HTTP status code.  
Processing  is  done  to  maintain  our  legitimate  interests  and  rests  on  the  legal  basis  provided  by Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR.  This  processing  serves  the  technical  administration  and  the  security  of  the website. The saved data are deleted after 10 days, provided that there is no legitimate reason to suspect  illegal  use  based  on  concrete  indications, and  additional  checking  and  processing  of  the information is required for this reason. 

#### 3\. Contact forms

There  are  various  contact  forms  on  our  website,  by means  of  which  you  can  send  us  messages, requests or questions on particular products. Here, your data are transferred encrypted. All data fields  marked  as  required  are  needed  for  processing your  requests.  Failure  to  provide  the information  will  have  the  consequence  that  we  are unable  to  process your  request.  Provision  of other data is voluntary. Alternatively, you may send us an email using the addresses provided. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 Par. 1 b) GDPR. 

#### 4\. dpa Whitepaper

In addition, you have the option of obtaining or ordering via our website the dpa whitepaper on various technical issues. We will need your name and email address in order to be able to provide you with a whitepaper. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 Par. 1 b) GDPR.

#### 5\. Newsletter

On our website we offer you the option of registering for our newsletter. Following registration, we will  provide  you  with  regular  information  on  current  offers,  products,  dates  and  employment vacancies  in  the  dpa  group  of  companies.  A  valid  email  address  is  required  to  register  for  the newsletter. When you subscribe to the newsletter on our website, we process your personal data, including  your  email  address,  your  name  and  where  applicable  the  company,  for  the  purpose  of dispatch and to check the ownership of the company. We also evaluate readers’ behaviour and the opening rate of our Newsletter. To this end, we analyse how often the newsletter is opened and the contributions that are clicked on. The legal basis for these processes is Art. 6 Par. 1 a) GDPR. You may withdraw consent at any time, by unsubscribing from our newsletter. For this purpose, you can make use of the unsubscribe link included in every email or send us a message via the abovementioned contact channels.  

You will first receive a registration email in order to verify the email address, which you will have to confirm by means of a link (Double Opt-In). On registering for the newsletter, we also save the IP address, as well as the date and time of the registration. Processing these details is necessary in order to be able to prove that consent has been given. The legal basis arises from our statutory obligation to prove that you have given consent (Art. 6 Par. 1 c) in combination with Art. 7 Par. 1 GDPR). 

**6\. Surveys**

We conduct occasional surveys on our website, our photo database and related services. Please note that we collect and process your data if you participate. The participation in our surveys is voluntary. 

The legal basis for the use of this information is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 a) GDPR. You can freely revoke your consent to the use of the information provided by you in a survey at any time with future effect.  Simply send us a message via the contact channels mentioned above. Please note that the processing, which has been carried out until your revocation, is not affected by this. 

**7\. Cookies**

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files that are saved by your browser when you visit a website. By this means, the browser used is identified and can be recognized by our webserver. Insofar as the use of cookies leads to the processing of personal data, this relies on the legal basis of Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR. This processing serves our legitimate interest of making our website more user-friendly, effective and secure.   
So-called “session cookies” are automatically deleted following the end of your visit. Other cookies (“persistent cookies”) are automatically deleted after a prescribed period, which may vary depending on the cookie. You can delete the cookies in the security settings of your browser at any time. You can reject the use of cookies categorically or in certain cases through your browser settings. The Bundesamt  für  Sicherheit  in  der  Informationstechnik  (Federal  German  Office  for  Information Security) provides  additional    information    on    this    at <https://www.bsi-fuer-buerger.de/BSIFB/DE/Empfehlungen/EinrichtungSoftware/EinrichtungBrowser/Sicherheitsmassnahmen/Cookies/cookies_node.html>

#### 8\. Google Analytics

To evaluate visits to our website, we make use of the service Google Analytics of Google LLC (1600

Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”). Google uses cookies that facilitate an analysis of your use of our website.   
The information generated by the cookie on the use of our website by the users is in general transmitted to a Google server in the United States und saved there. Google will use this information under contract from us in order to evaluate the use of our website by the users, to compile reports on the activities on the website and to provide us with services linked to the use of this website and internet use. We employ Google Analytics exclusively with IP anonymization activated. That means that the IP address of the user is abbreviated by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states party to the European Economic Area. The IP address transferred from the user’s browser is not combined with other Google data.  

The legal basis for data processing related to the Google Analytics service is Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR, and the processing serves the legitimate interest of an alysis of user behaviour on our website and possible needs-based configuration. You can prevent the saving of the cookies by means of the relevant setting in your browser software. You can also prevent capture of the information generated by the cookie by downloading and installing the browser plug-in in the following link: tools.google.com. For your current browser session you can also object to the use of Google Analytics by clicking on this: Link . 

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield agreement and thus provides a guarantee that it will abide by European data protection law (https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active.)).

#### 9\. Integrated Services and Third-party Content

On our website, we make use of services and content provided by third parties. Processing your IP address is technically necessary for these insertions, so that the content can be sent to your browser. For this reason, your IP address will be transmitted to the relevant third-party provider. This  data  processing  occurs  in  each  case  to  secure our  legitimate  interests  in  optimizing  and operating our website in an economic way and rests on the legal basis of Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR.  The programming language JavaScript is normally used for inserting the contents. You can in general reject  the  data  processing  by  deactivating  JavaScript  in  your  browser  or  installing  a  JavaScript blocker. Please note that this may result in limitations to the functionality of the website. For fonts we make use of MyFonts of MyFonts Inc. (500 Unicorn Park Drive, Woburn, MA 01801, USA). MyFonts Inc. is not certified under the Privacy Shield. 

For playing back videos, we use the service YouTube of YouTube LLC (901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; “YouTube”). As a subsidiary of Google LLC, YouTube is certified under the Privacy Shield agreement and as a result provides a guarantee that it will abide by European data protection law (https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active). 

#### 10\. Google AdWords Conversion Tracking

We use the online advertising program Google AdWord s from Google LLC, by means of which we link to adverts through Google. When you reach our website via a Google advert, Google places a cookie on your terminal (“conversion cookie”). Each AdWords customer is allocated a different conversion cookie, so that the cookies cannot be tracked via the websites of the different AdWords customers. The information gained with the help of the cookie is used to compile conversion statistics. In this way  we  ascertain  the  total  number  of  users  who  have  clicked  on  one  of  our  Google  adverts. However, we do not receive any information that would identify the user personally.  To the extent that personal data are processed here , this relies on the legal basis of Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR, and the data processing serves our legitimate economic interests. You are able to reject inclusion in conversion tracking by disabling the saving of cookies in your browser settings.  
Google is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield agreement and thus provides a suitable guarantee that it will abide by European data protection law (https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).  

#### 11\. Job applications

Via our website you have the option to apply for a vacant position or initiative with us or with other companies in the dpa group of companies. The transfer of your details via the website is of course encrypted. The details required are clear from the form for an online job application. If you do not provide these details, we will unfortunately be unable to process your application.  When  you  apply  for  a  position  with  the  dpa  group  of  companies,  your  job  application  data  are processed for the purposes linked to your interest in current or future employment with us and to the processing of your application. Your job application will be processed and seen solely by the relevant contact person. All staff entrusted with processing the details are under obligation to ensure the confidentiality of your data. The legal basis for the data processing is § 26 Par. 1 BDSG. Your job application details are in principle retained only up to the conclusion of the relevant application procedure. Continued storage occurs only insofar as statutory provisions prevent deletion, continued storage is required for the purpose of providing proof, or you take up a position with us. Otherwise we save your application details following the conclusion of an employment application procedure only if you have expressly consented to this. In this event we refer you to the fact that this consent can be withdrawn at any time in accordance with Art. 7 Par. 3 GDPR. The legality of the processing that has taken place up to the withdrawal on the basis of the consent is not affected by a withdrawal of this kind. 

#### 12\. Information on our Facebook sites

Apart from this website we also operate Facebook sites to represent our company and communicate with customers and other interested parties. In this respect we only process your personal data, if you interact with our Facebook sites, e.g. when you pass a comment, click on a like-button or send us a Facebook message.  
Legal basis for such data processing is Art. 6 Par. 1 b) GDPR (e.g. when you send us a contract relevant request). Apart from that, processing of your personal data can also take place on basis of your consent according to Art. 6 Par. 1 a) GDPR (e.g. if you are „liking“ or commenting a post of us, or if you upload or repost content on our site).  
You can revoke any given consent with respect to any future processing at any time, by deleting the comment or content. Please note, that any revocation of consent does not effect the legitamacy of the data processing prior to the revocation of consent.

Further, we assume joint control with Facebook Irland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin, for the processing of so-called Insights-data in connection with your visit on our Facebook sites. Facebook analyses user behaviour on our Facebook sites with the help of such Insights-data and provides us with these data in anonymized form. For this purpose we have concluded a joint controllership agreement with Facebook Ireland Ltd. that you may view at: www.facebook.com. This agreement includes without limitation that Facebook Ireland Ltd. commits itself to assume the primary responsibility according to the GDPR and to fulfill all duties under the GDPR with respect to the processing of Insights data. The processing serves our legitimate interests in the optimization and adequate composition of our Facebook sites, Art. 6 Par. 1 f) GDPR.

Please note, that by using and loading our Facebook sites your personal data are also processed by the companies operating „Facebook“, i.e. Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, that is residing in Ireland and Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California 94025 that is residing in the USA.  
Apart from data processing operations described above, Facebook also processes your personal data for analysis and advertising purposes respectively to supply you with personalized advertisements.  
In that process, as far as we know, Facebook uses cookies that record your user behaviour (and over the different devices you may use). As a consequence Facebook can display targeted advertisements within the Facebook platform as well as on third party websites. Please find further information in the Facebook privacy policy available at: [www.facebook.com](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).  
Facebook provides the opportunity to object to certain data processings; you may find respective information and options to opt-out under [www.facebook.com](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads). Please notice that according to the Facebook privacy policy user data will also be processed in the USA or other third countries (outside the European Union). Facebook only transfers user data to countries, for which an adequacy decision  of the European Commission pursuant to Art. 45 GDPR exists, or subject to appropriate safeguards according to Art. 46 GDPR.  
Facebook Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and consequentially offers an adequate level of data protection according to Art. 45 GDPR (https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active).   
In connection with the data processing by our Facebook sites you may also exercise your data subject rights (please see „Your rights“ herein below) against Facebook. You will find further information on this in the Facebook privacy policy. 

#### 13\. Your rights

As the person concerned, you have the right to assert your rights with respect to us. In particular, you have the following rights in this regard: 

• In accordance with Art. 15 GDPR and § 34 BDSG, you have the right to demand disclosure on whether  and,  where  applicable,  to  what  extent  we  process  personal  data  regarding  your person or not.  

• In accordance with Art. 16 GDPR, you have the right to demand the rectification of your data. 

• In accordance with Art. 17 GDPR and § 35 BDSG, you have the right to demand the erasure by us of your personal data. 

• In accordance with Art. 18 GDPR, you have the right to have the processing of you personal data restricted. 

• In accordance with Art. 20 GDPR, you have the right to receive the personal data concerning you that you  have  provided  to  us  in  a  structured, commonly  used  and machine-readable format, and to transmit these data to another responsible person. 

#### 14\. Right to object

In accordance with Art. 21 GDPR, you have the right  to object to any processing based on the legal basis of Art. 6 Par. 1 e) or f) GDPR. Insofar as personal data concerning you for the purpose of direct marketing including profiling is processed by us, you may object to this processing in accordance with Art. 21 Par. 2 and Par. 3 GDPR.

#### 15\. Withdrawal of consent

In accordance with Art. 7 Par. 3 GDPR, you may with draw consent previously given. The legality of the processing that has taken place up to the withdrawal on the basis of the consent is not affected by a withdrawal of this kind. 

#### 16\. Data Protection Officer

You can reach our Data Protection Officer at the following addresses:   
dpa Deutsche Presse-Agentur GmbH  
Data Protection Officer  
PO Box 13 02 82   
20102 Hamburg 

#### 16\. Complaint to a Supervisory Authority 

If  you  are  of  the  opinion  that  any  processing personal  data  related  to  you  infringes  the provisions of the GDPR, you have the right in accordance with Art. 77 GDPR to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.
